<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20210710</CreaDate><CreaTime>14382600</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><itemProps><imsContentType export="False"/></itemProps></DataProperties><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>NAP</ArcGISProfile></Esri><dataIdInfo><idCitation xmlns=""><resTitle>IPCC climate zones 1985-2015</resTitle><citRespParty xmlns=""><rpIndName>Philip Audebert</rpIndName><rpOrgName>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Climate Change Specialist</rpPosName><displayName>Philip Audebert</displayName><role><RoleCd value="011"/></role></citRespParty><citRespParty xmlns=""><rpIndName>Jason A. Tullis</rpIndName><rpOrgName>University of Arkansas</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Professor</rpPosName><displayName>Jason A. Tullis</displayName><displayName>Jason A. Tullis</displayName><role><RoleCd value="011"/></role></citRespParty><citRespParty xmlns=""><rpIndName>Stephen M. Ogle</rpIndName><rpOrgName>Colorado State University</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Professor</rpPosName><displayName>Stephen M. Ogle</displayName><role><RoleCd value="011"/></role></citRespParty><citRespParty xmlns=""><rpIndName>Martial Bernoux</rpIndName><rpOrgName>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Senior Natural Resources Officer</rpPosName><displayName>Martial Bernoux</displayName><role><RoleCd value="011"/></role></citRespParty><citRespParty xmlns=""><rpIndName>Laure-Sophie Schiettecatte</rpIndName><rpOrgName>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Climate Change Specialist</rpPosName><displayName>Laure-Sophie Schiettecatte</displayName><role><RoleCd value="011"/></role></citRespParty></idCitation><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV STYLE="font-size:12pt"&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This is an updated demonstration of the world climate zones described by IPCC in 2019. These zones are featured in an updated version of Figure 3A.5.1 in Volume 4, Chapter 3 of &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-style:italic;"&gt;2019 Refinement to the 2006 IPCC Guidelines for National Greenhouse Gas Inventories&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;. They demonstrate a geospatial representation of the classification scheme presented in Figure 3A.5.2 of the same chapter.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idPurp>This is an updated demonstration of the world climate zones described by IPCC in 2019.</idPurp><searchKeys><keyword>world climate</keyword></searchKeys><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="004"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="007"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="010"/></tpCat></dataIdInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20210722</mdDateSt><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></mdChar><dqInfo><dataLineage><statement>These climate zones were created by Philip Audebert (FAO), Jason Tullis (University of Arkansas), Stephen Ogle (Colorado State University), Martial Bernoux (FAO), and Laure-Sophie Schiettecatte (FAO). The zones are based on climate data from University of East Anglia Climate Research Unit et al. 2017 and global elevation data from USGS EROS Data Center 2008. The classification scheme found in Figure 3A.5.2 of Volume 4, Chapter 3 of "2019 Refinement to the 2006 IPCC Guidelines for National Greenhouse Gas Inventories" (Reddy et al. 2019) was first implemented using Google Earth Engine. To explore replicability, the same classification scheme was independently implemented using Esri's ArcGIS Pro 2.8.1 and Python 3.7.10. Strong correspondence was found in the results of the two workflows. The accompanying zones are based on the Esri/Python workflow. While Figure 3A.5.2 provides the logic used to generate the climate zones, the following workflow details are noted:

1) The USGS elevation data was spatially aggregated to the CRU TS4.00 half-degree resolution, and TS4.00 mean annual precipitation (MAP) areas not represented in the elevation data were assigned an elevation of 1 m.  

2) While most decisions in Figure 3A.5.2 were implemented using standard tools available through ArcGIS 2.8.1 ModelBuilder (e.g., Aggregate Multidimensional Raster, Raster Calculator, etc.), the "All Months Average &lt;10°C?" decision (interpreted as "each mean monthly temperature &lt; 10°C?") was implemented using a custom Python script to average the temperature data (1985-2015) by month, resulting in twelve averages per pixel (Jan, Feb, Mar, ...Dec).</statement><dataSource xmlns="" type=""><srcDesc>University of East Anglia Climatic Research Unit (CRU), Ian C Harris, and Philip D. Jones. 2017. “CRU TS4.00: Climatic Research Unit (CRU) Time-Series (TS) Version 4.00 of High Resolution Gridded Data of Month-by-Month Variation in Climate (Jan. 1901- Dec. 2015).” Application/xml. Centre for Environmental Data Analysis (CEDA). https://doi.org/10.5285/EDF8FEBFDAAD48ABB2CBAF7D7E846A86.</srcDesc></dataSource><dataSource xmlns="" type=""><srcDesc>USGS EROS Data Center. 2008. "Global Digital Elevation Model (GTOPO30)." Esri Data &amp; Maps. Redlands, California, USA.</srcDesc></dataSource><dataSource xmlns="" type=""><srcDesc>Reddy, S., L. Panichelli, R.M. Waterworth, S. Federici, C. Green, I. Jonckheere, S. Kahuri, W. Kurz, R. de Ligt J.P. Ometto, H. Petersson, E. Takahiro, P. Thomas, J. Tullis, Z. Somogyi, M. Pandya, M.T. Rocha and K. Suzuki. 2019. “Consistent Representation of Lands” in 2019 Refinement to the 2006 IPCC Guidelines for National Greenhouse Gas Inventories, Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change Task Force on National Greenhouse Gas Inventories. Adopted at 49th Session of the IPCC, Kyoto, Japan, 8-12 May, 2019.</srcDesc></dataSource></dataLineage></dqInfo><mdLang><languageCode value="eng"/></mdLang></metadata>
